<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Vietnam_history</string>

    <string name="event1">Mythical Era: The Legend of Lạc Long Quân and Âu Cơ</string>
    <string name="event2">2879 BC: The Hùng Kings and the founding of Văn Lang</string>
    <string name="event3">938 AD: The Battle of Bạch Đằng River</string>
    <string name="event4">968 AD: The Đinh Dynasty and the unification of Vietnam</string>
    <string name="event5">1009-1225: The Lý Dynasty and the establishment of Thăng Long (Hanoi)</string>
    <string name="event6">1225-1400: The Trần Dynasty and the Mongol invasions</string>
    <string name="event7">1400-1407: The Hồ Dynasty and the Ming occupation</string>
    <string name="event8">1428: The Lê Dynasty and the restoration of independence</string>
    <string name="event9">Late 18th century: The Tây Sơn Rebellion</string>
    <string name="event10">1802-1945: The Nguyễn Dynasty and the unification of Vietnam</string>
    <string name="event11">Mid-19th century to 1945: French colonization and the resistance movements</string>
    <string name="event12">August 1945: The August Revolution and the declaration of independence</string>
    <string name="event13">1946-1954: The First Indochina War</string>
    <string name="event14">1954: The Geneva Accords and the division of Vietnam</string>
    <string name="event15">1955-1975: American War (The Vietnam War)</string>
    <string name="event16">1968: The Tet Offensive</string>
    <string name="event17">April 30, 1975: The Fall of Saigon</string>
    <string name="event18">Post-1975: Post-war reconstruction and reunification</string>
    <string name="event19">1986: The “Đổi Mới” economic reforms</string>
    <string name="event20">Post-1986: Vietnam’s integration into the global economy</string>
    <string name="event21">The role of women in Vietnamese history</string>
    <string name="event22">Traditional Vietnamese festivals</string>
    <string name="event23">The history of Vietnamese cuisine</string>
    <string name="event24">The influence of Confucianism, Buddhism, and Taoism</string>
    <string name="event25">The history of Vietnamese art and literature</string>
    <string name="event26">The impact of colonial architecture in Vietnam</string>
    <string name="event27">The history of Vietnamese education</string>
    <string name="event28">The role of the Vietnamese diaspora</string>
    <string name="event29">Modern political developments in Vietnam</string>
    <string name="event30">Vietnam’s role in ASEAN and international relations</string>

    <string name="eventDescription1">This legend tells the story of the mythical ancestors of the Vietnamese people. Lạc Long Quân, a dragon lord, and Âu Cơ, a fairy, had 100 children, who are considered the ancestors of the Vietnamese people. This legend symbolizes the unity and origin of the Vietnamese nation.</string>
    <string name="eventDescription2">The Hùng Kings are credited with founding the first Vietnamese state, Văn Lang, around 2879 BC. This period marks the beginning of Vietnamese civilization and the establishment of a structured society.</string>
    <string name="eventDescription3">In 938 AD, General Ngô Quyền defeated the Southern Han invaders at the Bạch Đằng River, securing Vietnam’s independence from Chinese rule. This battle is celebrated as a pivotal moment in Vietnamese history.</string>
    <string name="eventDescription4">Đinh Bộ Lĩnh unified Vietnam in 968 AD, establishing the Đinh Dynasty. He declared himself Emperor and named the country Đại Cồ Việt, marking the beginning of a centralized Vietnamese state.</string>
    <string name="eventDescription5">The Lý Dynasty (1009-1225) is known for establishing Thăng Long (modern-day Hanoi) as the capital. This period saw significant cultural and economic development.</string>
    <string name="eventDescription6">The Trần Dynasty (1225-1400) successfully repelled three Mongol invasions in the 13th century. This era is marked by military prowess and the strengthening of the Vietnamese state.</string>
    <string name="eventDescription7">The Hồ Dynasty (1400-1407) was short-lived, ending with the Ming occupation of Vietnam. This period was marked by significant upheaval and resistance against foreign rule.</string>
    <string name="eventDescription8">Lê Lợi led a successful rebellion against the Ming, establishing the Lê Dynasty in 1428. This period is known for restoring Vietnamese independence and consolidating power.</string>
    <string name="eventDescription9">The Tây Sơn brothers led a rebellion in the late 18th century, overthrowing the ruling Lê Dynasty and defeating foreign invaders. Their rule brought significant social and economic reforms.</string>
    <string name="eventDescription10">The Nguyễn Dynasty (1802-1945) unified Vietnam under Emperor Gia Long. This period saw the consolidation of Vietnamese territory and the establishment of a centralized administration.</string>
    <string name="eventDescription11">French colonization began in the mid-19th century, leading to significant changes in Vietnamese society. Resistance movements, such as those led by Phan Bội Châu and Ho Chi Minh, emerged in response to colonial rule.</string>
    <string name="eventDescription12">In August 1945, the Viet Minh led a successful revolution against Japanese occupation, leading to the declaration of independence by Ho Chi Minh on September 2, 1945.</string>
    <string name="eventDescription13">The First Indochina War (1946-1954) was fought between the Viet Minh and French colonial forces. It ended with the Geneva Accords, which temporarily divided Vietnam at the 17th parallel.</string>
    <string name="eventDescription14">The Geneva Accords of 1954 temporarily divided Vietnam into North and South at the 17th parallel, setting the stage for future conflict.</string>
    <string name="eventDescription15">The Vietnam War (1955-1975) was a conflict between North Vietnam, supported by its communist allies, and South Vietnam, backed by the United States. It ended with the fall of Saigon and the reunification of Vietnam.</string>
    <string name="eventDescription16">The Tet Offensive in 1968 was a major turning point in the Vietnam War. It was a series of surprise attacks by the Viet Cong and North Vietnamese forces, leading to significant changes in U.S. public opinion about the war.</string>
    <string name="eventDescription17">On April 30, 1975, North Vietnamese forces captured Saigon, marking the end of the Vietnam War and leading to the reunification of Vietnam under communist control.</string>
    <string name="eventDescription18">After the war, Vietnam underwent significant reconstruction and reunification efforts, facing numerous economic and social challenges.</string>
    <string name="eventDescription19">Introduced in 1986, the Đổi Mới (Renovation) reforms transformed Vietnam’s economy from a centrally planned system to a socialist-oriented market economy, leading to significant economic growth.</string>
    <string name="eventDescription20">Since the Đổi Mới reforms, Vietnam has increasingly integrated into the global economy, joining organizations such as the World Trade Organization (WTO) and signing various trade agreements.</string>
    <string name="eventDescription21">Women have played crucial roles in Vietnamese history, from legendary figures like the Trưng Sisters to modern leaders and activists, contributing significantly to the nation’s development.</string>
    <string name="eventDescription22">Traditional festivals, such as Tết (Lunar New Year) and Mid-Autumn Festival, hold deep historical and cultural significance, reflecting Vietnam’s rich heritage and customs.</string>
    <string name="eventDescription23">Vietnamese cuisine is known for its diverse flavors and regional specialties. Its history reflects the country’s agricultural practices, cultural exchanges, and colonial influences.</string>
    <string name="eventDescription24">Confucianism, Buddhism, and Taoism have profoundly influenced Vietnamese culture, shaping its values, social structures, and spiritual practices.</string>
    <string name="eventDescription25">Vietnamese art and literature have evolved over centuries, reflecting the country’s historical experiences, cultural exchanges, and artistic innovations.</string>
    <string name="eventDescription26">French colonial architecture has left a lasting impact on Vietnam’s urban landscapes, with iconic buildings and structures that blend European and local styles.</string>
    <string name="eventDescription27">Vietnamese education has a long history, from traditional Confucian academies to modern institutions, reflecting the country’s emphasis on learning and scholarship.</string>
    <string name="eventDescription28">The Vietnamese diaspora has played a significant role in globalizing Vietnamese culture and contributing to the economies and societies of their host countries.</string>
    <string name="eventDescription29">Modern political developments in Vietnam include the consolidation of the Communist Party’s power, economic reforms, and efforts to address social and environmental challenges.</string>
    <string name="eventDescription30">Vietnam is an active member of ASEAN and plays a significant role in regional and international relations, contributing to peace, stability, and economic cooperation in Southeast Asia.</string>
</resources>